<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grad School on Science in Progress</title>
    <link>/categories/grad-school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grad School on Science in Progress</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/grad-school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#9 Abbie Kropf - Entomology &amp; Perseverance in Grad School</title>
      <link>/2018/09/22/9-abbie-kropf-entomology-perseverance-in-grad-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/22/9-abbie-kropf-entomology-perseverance-in-grad-school/</guid>
      <description>In this episode I chat with Abbie Kropf a 2nd year PhD student at Iowa State University. Abbie is in the department of entomology at Iowa State. In this episode, we talk about how Abbie started in her Masters research in Costa Rica. She spend multiple seasons in Costa Rica studying forest fragmentation with Dr. Mike Wasserman and Dr. Peter Beck.
We also have a great discussion about perserserverance in grad school and suggestions for finding grad school labs that will be a good fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#5 Dan Clark - Grad School Decisions</title>
      <link>/2018/05/21/5-dan-clark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/21/5-dan-clark/</guid>
      <description>In this episode I chat with Dan Clark, a PhD candidate in Ecology and Evolution at Rutgers University. During this podcast, Dan and I discuss some of the many decisions that prospective grad students have to make when applying to programs. We talk about things ranging from the differences between MS and PhD programs and living in places that get so much snow! Dan received his masters from CUNY-ESF, and it&amp;rsquo;s great to hear his research path and how he made decisions about grad school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#3 Nicholas Lyon - Research Talk</title>
      <link>/2018/04/11/3-nicholas-lyon-research-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/11/3-nicholas-lyon-research-talk/</guid>
      <description>How can agricultural pastures be managed to support a community pollinators? Nicholas Lyon joins me on Science in Progress to chat about his research on this subject and much more. Nick is the first guest in a series of research talks we&amp;rsquo;ll record focused on the awesome research that student ecologists are conducting. Nick is a masters student at Iowa State University and did his undergraduate at the University of Puget Sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#1 Katie Thompson - Teaching in Grad School</title>
      <link>/2018/03/25/episode-1-taing-in-grad-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/25/episode-1-taing-in-grad-school/</guid>
      <description>The very first episode of Science in Progress is now available. In this episode, I&amp;rsquo;m joined by Katie Thompson of Iowa State University. As a PhD student, Katie studies lichen diversity in Iowa. Katie also has been teaching since her early days in grad school and she shares some of the techinques that she uses in the classroom to keep students engaged and excited. Big thanks to Katie for joining me on the first episode.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>